[
    {
        "Question": "In Gethsemane, Jesus prayed saying \"O my Father, if it be possible, let this cup pass from me: nevertheless not as I will, but as thou wilt\". How many times did he repeat this prayer?",
        "Answer": "Three(3) times. Matt 26:39;Matt26:42;Matt26:44"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Paul and Silas met Barjesus in?",
        "Answer": "Paphos (Acts 13:6)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What did Judas buy with the 30 pieces of silver he got from betraying Jesus?",
        "Answer": "He didn't buy anything. He cast down the pieces of silver in the temple and departed (Matthew 27:5). However, Acts 1:18 referring to Judas states, \"Now this man purchased a field with the reward of iniquity…\""
    },
    {
        "Question": "What was the money(30 pieces of silver) used for eventually? ",
        "Answer": "It was used to buy a potter's field (called the field of blood) to bury strangers in it (Matthew 27: 7-8)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Why does the Bible state that we should keep our heart with all diligence?",
        "Answer": "For out of it are the issues of life (Proverbs 4:23)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "\"Neither have I gone back from the commandment of his lips; I have esteemed the words of his mouth more than my necessary food\". Who made this statement?",
        "Answer": "Job (Job 23:12)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "According to James, let every man be swift to ........, slow to …....., slow to ........",
        "Answer": "hear;speak;wrath (James 1:19)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "In 1 Samuel, stubbornness is referred to as iniquity and ….....? ",
        "Answer": "Idolatory (1 Samuel 15:23)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who was the king who wrote the book of Proverbs?",
        "Answer": "Solomon (Proverbs 1:1)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Where did the pharisees claim Jesus got his power to cast out devils?",
        "Answer": "Beelzebub (Matthew 12: 24)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "According to 2 Peter 3, what is God's will towards man?",
        "Answer": "\"…not willing that any should perish, but that all should come to repentance\" (2 Peter 3:9)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Paul was stoned at?",
        "Answer": "Lystra (Acts 14:19)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "\"For my thoughts are not your thoughts, neither are your ways my ways, saith the Lord\" is from which book of the Bible? ",
        "Answer": "Isiah 55:8"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who was the woman that was brought to David when he was old?",
        "Answer": "Abishag, a Shunammite (1 Kings 1:1-3)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What was the name of the prince that defiled Dinah, the daughter of Jacob?",
        "Answer": "Shechem (Genesis 34:2)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "\"He that blesseth his friend with a loud voice, rising early in the morning, it shall be counted a …........... to him\"",
        "Answer": "Curse (Proverbs 27: 14)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "John left Paul and Barnabas in?",
        "Answer": "Perga in Pamphylia (Acts 13: 13)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "1 Thessalonians 5: 17 goes thus…",
        "Answer": "Pray without ceasing"
    },
    {
        "Question": "According to Numbers 12, why did Miriam and Aaron speak againt Moses?",
        "Answer": "Because of the Ethiopian woman whom he had married (Numbers 12:1)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "\"And we know that all things work together for good to them that love God…..\". Complete this passage ",
        "Answer": "To them who are called according to his purpose(Romans 8: 28)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "In the parable, what did the servant whose debt was forgiven do?",
        "Answer": "He laid hands on a fellowservant who owed him 100 pence and took him by the throat demanding the fellowservant pay his debt (Matthew 18:28)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "1 John refers to a man that says he loves God and hateth his brother as a?",
        "Answer": "Liar (1 John 4:20)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Why did Paul leave Trophimus behind?",
        "Answer": "Because he was sick (2 Timothy 4:20)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is the meaning of Elymas? ",
        "Answer": "The sorcerer (Acts 13:8)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "\"LAMED. For ever, O LORD, thy word is settled in heaven\" is from which book of the Bible?",
        "Answer": "Psalms 119:89"
    },
    {
        "Question": "When King Herod died, he was eaten by?",
        "Answer": "Worms (Acts 12: 23)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Why was Haman full of wrath?",
        "Answer": "Mordecai neither bowed nor did him reverance (Esther 3:5)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "In the book of Acts when Paul said \"…Trouble not yourselves, for his life is in him\". Whose life was he referring to?",
        "Answer": "Eutychus (Acts 20: 9-10)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How many years did King Abijah of Judah reign?",
        "Answer": "Three(3) years (1 Kings 15: 2)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Lamentations 3: 23 goes thus…",
        "Answer": "They are new every morning: great is thy faithfulness"
    },
    {
        "Question": "According to the book of James, whosoever will be a friend of the world is?",
        "Answer": "The enemy of God (James 4:4)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What lie did Abraham tell Abilemech, King of Gerar?",
        "Answer": "That Sarah was his sister (Genesis 20:2)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "According to the book of Colossians, charity is referred to as?",
        "Answer": "The bond of perfectness (Colossians 3 : 14)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who is the father of Hoshea?",
        "Answer": "Elah (2 Kings 17:1)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "According to 1 Samuel 2: 30, \"for them that honour me I will honour, and they that despise me…...\"",
        "Answer": "Shall be lightly esteemed (1 Samuel 2: 30)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Naomi said, \"Call me not Naomi, call me Mara…\". Why did she say so?",
        "Answer": "Because the Almighty hath dealt very bitterly with her (Ruth 1: 20)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Hoshea was servant to the king of Assyria. What was the name of the king?",
        "Answer": "Shalmaneser (2 Kings 17:3)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "When the Lord appeared to Solomon in a dream in Gibeon, what did Solomon ask the Lord for?",
        "Answer": "An underderstanding heart to judge the people (1 Kings 3:9)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "According to the book of John, \"A man can receive nothing, except…\"?",
        "Answer": "It be given him from heaven (John 3:27)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "\"Behold, what manner of love the Father hath bestowed upon us….\". Complete this Bible passage",
        "Answer": "That we should be called the sons of God: therefore the world knoweth us not, because it knew him not (1 John 3:1)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "According to James, what should anyone that lack wisdom do?",
        "Answer": "Let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him (James 1:5)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "\"But ye are forgers of lies, ye are all physicians of no value\". Who made this statement?",
        "Answer": "Job (Job 13:4)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "\"Sanctify them through thy truth: thy word is truth\" can be found in what book of the Bible?",
        "Answer": "John 17:17"
    },
    {
        "Question": "According to Matthew, whosoever shall exalt himself shall be ….. and he that shall humble himself shall be ….....",
        "Answer": "Abased; exalted (Matther 23:12)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Blessed are the peacemakers….",
        "Answer": "For they shall be called the children of God (Matthew 5:9)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "According to Galatians, \"he that soweth of the flesh shall of the flesh reap …... ; but he that soweth of the Spirit shall of the Spirit reap …...\". Complete the passage",
        "Answer": "Corruption; life everlasting (Galatians 6:8)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "According to James,  \"Blessed is the man that endureth temptation: for when he is tried, he shall receive…......\". Complete the passage",
        "Answer": "The crown of life (James 1:12)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Why did Shalmaneser, King of Assyria shut Hoshea up and bind him in prison?",
        "Answer": "The King found conspiracy in Hoshea (2 Kings 17:4)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "\"It is more blessed to give than to receive\" can be found in which book of the Bible?",
        "Answer": "Acts 20:35"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is the name of Samuel's second son ane he was a judge in?",
        "Answer": "Abiah; Beersheba (1 Samuel 8:2)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "When Naomi's husband died, she was left with her two sons. What are their names (husband and sons)?",
        "Answer": "Husband -- Elimelech; Sons -- Mahlon and Chilion (Ruth 1: 3)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "When Simon Peter was brought to Jesus, Jesus said \"Thou art Simon the son of …..: thou shalt be called Cephas\". What does Cephas mean and Simon the son of?",
        "Answer": "Stone; Jona (John 1: 42)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What did Paul have in common with Aquila and his wife, Priscilla?",
        "Answer": "They were all tentmakers (Acts 18: 2-3)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "According to Proverbs, when the wicked beareth rule, what do the people do?",
        "Answer": "Mourn (Proverbs 29:2)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How does the book of Genesis regard Noah?",
        "Answer": "As a just man (Genesis 6: 9)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Blessed are they which do hunger and thirst after righteousness…..",
        "Answer": "For they shall be filled (Matthew 5:9)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "\"If any man have ears to hear, let him hear\" is from which book in the Bible?",
        "Answer": "Mark 4:23"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How many chapters are in the book of Acts?",
        "Answer": "Twenty-eight(28)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How did Jezebel die?",
        "Answer": "She was thrown out a window (II Kings 9:30-33)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who reigned after Hezekiah?",
        "Answer": "Manasseh (II Kings 20:21)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How old was he (Manasseh) when he bagan to reign, how many years did he reign for and what was his mothers name?",
        "Answer": "Began reign--Twelve years old(12); Reigned for-- Fifty-five years(55); Mother's name--Hephzibah "
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who were the men nominated to replace Judas and who eventually replaced Judas?",
        "Answer": "Joseph and Mathias; Mathias (Acts 1:23; Acts 1:26)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Noah had three sons. What were their names?",
        "Answer": "Shem, Ham and Japheth (Genesis 6:10)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What was the fashion of Noah's ark? (Length, Breadth and Height)",
        "Answer": "Length-- 300 cubits; Breadth-- 50 cubits; Height-- 30 cubits"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who planned to kill Mordecai?",
        "Answer": "Haman (Esther 3:6)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How was Haman killed?",
        "Answer": "He was hanged on the gallows that he had prepared for Mordecai (Esther 7:10)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How high were the gallows?",
        "Answer": "50 cubits high (Esther 7:9)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Blessed are the poor in spirit…",
        "Answer": "For theirs is the kingdom of Heaven (Matthew 5:3)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What was the ninth plague?",
        "Answer": "Darkness for three days (Exodus: 10:21-22)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "In the city of Lystra, the people called Barnabas Jupiter and Paul Mercurius after they perfomed a miracle. What was the miracle?",
        "Answer": "Healing of a cripple (Acts 14: 8-12)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How long did Josiah reign and what was his mothers name?",
        "Answer": "Thirty one(31) years; Jedidah (II Kings 22: 1)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "The disciples were called Christians first at ….?",
        "Answer": "Antioch (Acts 11:26)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "According to Proverbs, whoso keepeth his mouth and his tongue keepeth his soul from what?",
        "Answer": "Troubles (Proverbs 21: 23)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "In the book of Philemon, who is Paul's fellow prisoner?",
        "Answer": "Epaphras (Philemon 1:23)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "David pretended to be mad before …..........., the king of ….......... to avoid been captured and killed. ",
        "Answer": "Achish, king of Gath (1 Samuel 21: 10-13)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who thought Jesus was a gardener when she saw Him after He has risen?",
        "Answer": "Mary Magdalene (John 20:15)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What Roman ruler expelled all Jews out of Rome in the days of the early Church?",
        "Answer": "Claudius (Acts 18:2)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who sold his land, brought the money and laid it at the apostles' feet?",
        "Answer": "Barnabas (Acts 4:37)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What does his name(Barnabas) mean? ",
        "Answer": "The son of consolation (Acts 4: 36)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who was the prophet who spoke of the Messiah as a \"man of sorrows\"?",
        "Answer": "Isiah (Isiah 53:3)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "The book of Colossians regards fornication, uncleanness, inordinate affection, evil concupiscence and covetousnes as ….........?",
        "Answer": "Idolatory (Colossians 3:5)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Paul was brought to a meeting of the Areopagus at …...?",
        "Answer": "Thessalonica (Acts 17:1, 19:19)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Paul and Barnabas has a disagreement over John, whose surname was Mark. What was the reason for this disagreement? ",
        "Answer": "Barnabas was determined to take with them Mark but Paul was against it as Mark had departed from them from Pamphylia (Acts 15: 37:38)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who predicted about famine during the time of Claudius?",
        "Answer": "Agabus (Acts 11:28)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "\"I have never eaten anything that is common or unclean\". Who made this statement?",
        "Answer": "Peter (Acts 10: 14)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who was the mother of Moses?",
        "Answer": "Jochebed (Exodus 6:20)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Moses had …... sons?",
        "Answer": "Two (Acts 7:29)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is the first Commandment?",
        "Answer": "Thou shalt have no other gods before me (Exodus 20:3)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "\"And now abideth faith, hope, charity, these three; but the greatest of these is …......\"",
        "Answer": "Charity (1 Corinthians 13: 13)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "According to Matthew, what should we do to those that despitefully use us and persecute us?",
        "Answer": "Pray for them (Matthew 5:44)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What was Barnabas relationship with Marcus?",
        "Answer": "Marcus is his nephew (Colossians 4:10)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Jesus said replying the devil, \"…It is written, that man shall not live by bread alone, but by every word of God\". What part of the scripture did he quote here?",
        "Answer": "Deuteronomy 8:3"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What did Paul recommend to Timothy for his stomach's sake and his infirmities?",
        "Answer": "A little wine (1 Timothy 5:23)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "\"…with his stripes we are healed\" --Isiah 53:5. In which other book of the Bible can we find a similar statement? ",
        "Answer": "1 Peter 2:24"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Shortest book in the New Testament?",
        "Answer": "3 John"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who was the mother of Samuel?",
        "Answer": "Hannah (1 Samuel: 1:20)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who was the woman who anointed the feet of Jesus with expensive perfume?",
        "Answer": "Mary of Bethany (John 12:3)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "In the book of John, which disciple of Jesus was called a thief?",
        "Answer": "Judas (John 12: 4-6)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who was the first martyr in the Bible?",
        "Answer": "Abel (Genesis 4:8)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Joab had an affair with one of Saul's concubine. What was her name?",
        "Answer": "Rizpah, daughter of Aiah (2 Samuel 3:7)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What was David's first born?",
        "Answer":"Amnon (2 Samuel3:2)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who killed Abner, the son of Ner",
        "Answer": "Joab (2 Samuel 3:27)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What was the name of Joab's brother murdered by Abner?",
        "Answer": "Asahel (2 Samuel 2:22-23)"
    },
    {
        "Question": "When Solomon heard David was in the wilderness of Engedi, how many chosen men did he take to seek him(David)?",
        "Answer": "Three thousand chosen men (1 Samuel 24:2)"
    }
]